[music]
>> Winter to me is the time for slowness,
to hurry a little less and be a little
more.
To steal that [music] extra minute under
a warm fleece blanket and above all
else, the time for visiting cozy
bookstores and whiling away the hours
absorbed [music]
in a good story.
This is my first winter as a bookstore
owner and I've been excited and
naturally nervous.
I had no idea what to expect last
[music] December and the events that
played out that month taught me in some
very big ways to [music] let go and know
that unexpected things will always
happen.
So settle in with a cup of tea and let
me tell you about our winter adventures
thus far.
It begins with a few projects I've
wanted to do for a while. I'm proud to
[music] say that we finally dedicated a
whole two bookcases to used books.
My lovely friend also painted this
beautiful mural for us and my husband
Luke built a shelf to display and sell
crystals, [music]
a passion of his.
We were both very excited to go into the
holiday season [music]
knowing that with snow comes skiers who
also love to take breaks and spend them
at a warm bookstore.
So we [music] dedicated an entire
weekend as a family to decorate and
pretty up the bookstore so that it can
look as beautiful as possible for the
year's end.
But of course, that also meant that we
had to take time outside of our work to
enjoy the snowfall as well
and that was well worth it.
One, two, three.
Okay,
that's the Easter.
Three, two,
one.
>> [laughter]
>> Yay!
Yay!
There is no magic that can quite compare
to soft snow falling in a quiet world.
I'm glad I can share this special wonder
with my son who turned a year and a half
last December.
I would love to tell you that our
December went as planned with no
unexpected challenges, but life just
doesn't work that way and it's up to us
to accept that or fight it for the rest
of our lives, I have come to understand.
Because if any of you have been
following the news in the Pacific
Northwest, you would know that in early
December we had historic flooding in the
entire state. Harsh rain storms of warm
water that melted most of our snow and
left us with an icy muddy mess, rushing
rivers full of murky water and thousands
of people homeless.
It was a scary time and to be honest,
coupled with the stress of seeing
friends having their houses flooded,
wondering what this meant for our
businesses, dealing with a big issue
with my publisher I'll talk more about
later and being a highly sensitive
person experiencing a very big life
change, I found myself having anxiety
attacks.
As you may know if you watched past
videos, I recovered from a nervous
breakdown several years ago and since
then I've made incredible progress by
learning to listen to my body and soul
and manage overwhelm.
>> [music]
>> But no healing journey is meant to be
perfect. I still have anxiety at times
and this was a difficult month. [music]
However, I do recognize how far I've
come. Just a few years ago I would have
never been able to manage all this at
once
>> [music]
>> and I responded to this time of stress
with a lot of journaling, meditation,
nature walks and of course some much
needed arts and crafts projects to focus
my mind on the present. I spent my time
outside of work making little
decorations for my home, staying present
to my emotions and knowing that they
would soon pass.
If there is any word I would offer you
as advice to get through any difficult
time,
it is to be gentle. Be gentle towards
yourself.
Sometimes there's nothing to resolve,
nothing [music] to do.
Sometimes you just need to be allowed to
feel.
Despite everything going on, I actually
got a very exciting package in the mail
on the 13th and I couldn't wait to share
it with you.
This is just about the most exciting day
I've had this year.
Ah!
>> [screaming]
>> So over 3 years ago when I was going
through a challenging time, I found
resilience and hope and was able to
recharge through a very important
creative project that has culminated
into the woods and wisp. This is a book
that I wrote for both children and
adults, especially whimsical adults that
hold a sense of childlike wonder in
their heart and are also a fan of
animals and nature and exploring topics
that are deep and poignant about our
soul and our place in the world and
finding hope in a very gentle way that
isn't scary or sad, but instead
uplifting. And so I really wanted to
write a book like that not only for
myself to help me through that difficult
time working through a lot of anxiety
and becoming a much more resilient and
stronger person, but I also wanted to
write this book for my son. And there is
a dedication for my son Caspian.
Beware, there are grown-ups out there
who will insist the world is a bleak and
dark place. They are right, but only a
little.
There will be others who look upon that
darkness and cry bitterly. Then they
tilt their heads up and notice the
stars.
They face [music] both pain and love
with an open heart. They're not afraid
to jump in rain puddles and belly laugh.
They spread kindness and make the world
a better place just by being their
truest selves.
>> [music]
>> They find reasons to hope each day.
They have discovered the secret, the way
things truly are. It takes courage, but
you have that in abundance. With a love
that extends to the stars and beyond,
your mother.
P.S. If you ever need me and I'm not
there, go befriend a tree.
No doubt, I'll be close by. The Wood and
Whispers about a rabbit who goes on an
adventure to find her lost friend who is
going through a difficult time. There
are quite a few
illustrations. I filled the book with as
many illustrations as I could. The main
character that is Wisp. So, some of you
may know that I wrote The Cottage Fairy
Companion and that is a book I wrote uh
quite a long time ago. It feels like a
lifetime ago now. Something very
unfortunate has recently happened in
regards to that book.
The publishing company that published
that book went bankrupt [music]
and unfortunately it was a very
disorganized process where there were a
lot of people left out of the loop
including myself and I, along with many
many authors, were never paid for well
over a year of book sales and their
[music] work. It's been a really tragic
tragic experience. I've had weeks to
process but initially I was very sad. I
even contacted a lawyer at one point
>> [music]
>> to try to understand what my rights were
because it was very very difficult to
even get the files of my book back and I
wasn't getting any clear communication
from the company. But then I discovered
that lawyers can be $400 an hour to
consult [laughter] and so I did realize
that that probably wasn't a realistic
avenue to go down. So, I ended up not
doing that because
who can who can afford that? But I did
have feelings of anger, disappointment,
frustration, and mostly just heartbreak
for other authors. And it is frustrating
to have a book still out there where I
don't even know how to get access back
to me and
I don't know. But I did want to explain
the situation because I just wanted you
to know that if you do purchase The
Cottage Fairy Companion and you find it
somewhere online, it is no longer
unfortunately
affiliated with me even though I am the
author because
it has been [music] somewhat helpful
honestly to have this bad news during
such an important time as writing a new
book. And I learned from the past and
this book is completely self-published.
I did not want to work with a company
again mostly because I just can't
control the quality of the book itself
and the quality of the experience. And
so I um am older and wiser now and I
really wanted to share something that I
was truly truly proud of that was
exactly how I wanted it to be. I've
always felt that there should be a genre
for children and adults to share
together. Grown-up children out there
that really still enjoy whimsical and
cozy reads and I wanted this book to
feel very peaceful and cozy and sweet
and still thoughtful and meaningful. So,
I hope that will be the case for you if
you decide to purchase it. Of course,
there is no obligation to purchase it
but I do now have it available. I do
recommend you pre-order it through my
Etsy shop. It will take me a little bit
longer to fulfill those those orders.
I'm going to print on demand so 1 to 2
months to have the book completely ready
to go and at your door. But I will be
able to control the quality, make sure
it's perfect, I will be able to package
it in some beautiful wrapping paper that
I have found. I'm going to have a little
wax seal to seal it. I will [music] be
sending so many well wishes and fairy
dust with the order. And if you order
through my Etsy shop, you will receive a
matching bookmark and two prints and
quote cards of kind of my early sketches
regarding the book. It's not often that
a creature stops what they're doing and
looks up.
Clouds don't mean that the stars are not
there. So, if you do wish to support
this creative project, please feel free.
I will leave all the information down
below. I am so very very excited about
this. Um this is
I think the book I always truly wanted
to write.
Thankfully, by mid-December the snow had
started to return and we finally got a
few ski trails open.
While it still hasn't been the best
winter, we have dealt with it as best we
could and ended the year with a very
busy holiday which was wonderful and so
encouraging.
>> [music]
>> My internal turmoil healed and things
started to feel peaceful once again
reminding me that all things shall
indeed pass.
We just need to give ourselves time.
So, it is a very cold winter morning.
Snow is covering the trees. The windows
are frosty. I have a warm cup of tea and
once again, like I said in my last
video, I don't believe any video related
to a bookstore can be created without at
the very least talking about books that
at one point I have read.
>> [laughter]
>> And so I thought that I would share with
you a rather non-exhaustive
list of books that I read this year and
how I felt about them. Baby turned into
a toddler this year and I have been
running around constantly and often very
overwhelmed and overstimulated as many
people, especially highly sensitive
people, would be at this phase of
parenthood. And so I have not been
tracking my reading. I'm sure there's a
lot of books that I have read that I
can't either remember that I've read
them because they were early in the year
or I'm just they're just leaving my mind
at this moment. One of my very favorite
books that I've read this year is The
Wheel of the Year by Jessica Row and
Fiona Cook. The reason I picked it up
was definitely because Jessica Row is
one of my favorite illustrators. They
make absolutely beautiful beautiful art
and this book goes through every season
of the year inspired by kind of
ancestral ideas in the northern
hemisphere and just going through some
really fun activities and things you can
do to enjoy the season. In a similar
vein of interests, I read To Bless the
Space Between Us by John O'Donohue. His
writing and poetry is just so beautiful.
I think that it doesn't matter what
belief system you have, whether you are
religious or spiritual or none of the
above, I believe you still can find
beauty and value in the way that he sees
the world and portrays it in words. No
Mud, No Lotus, of course I'm a huge fan
of this author
>> [laughter]
>> and I've read pretty much all of his
books.
I had in some ways a difficult year.
There were very stressful moments and
this book was a quiet gentle reminder of
many things I've already read
but it was still special nonetheless. I
also read The Magician's Daughter by
H.G. Perry. I read this one a while ago
and I don't think I ever actually got to
finish it so I actually did this time.
H.G. Perry is one of my favorite
authors. Everything he writes is just
magical and his writing style is just
fantastic.
It is a slow-paced book. It is
feels very nostalgic, very atmospheric.
Um it's not like a really super crazy
entrancing read. Um there were times
where I just really settled into the
slowness and coziness of the story and
it reminded me a little bit of The Mists
of Avalon and The Mists of Avalon is one
of my favorite books of all time. How it
expresses characters and the story of
King Arthur is just so original and so
incredible. This book I still have not
finished but I've mostly finished it so
I'm thinking I'm going to finish it by
the end of December. It is The Druids.
This is a deeply researched book and it
it can be a very very dry very dry at
some points. Um but I did really want to
learn about this group of people from
the past. I reread The House Witch this
year because once again, when I was
having a very stressful month midway
through the year, I really needed
something cozy and something that just
reminded me of the truly important
things in life. Making food,
taking care of your home, doing simple
everyday acts of kindness, and
connecting with your pets. And this book
is the ultimate cozy read, I think. It
just feels
so wonderful and it was just so fun to
read.
>> [clears throat]
>> And so, I picked up this book is
described as fantasy meets Sherlock
Holmes, and so I just had to give it a
go. It was incredibly violent. It was
dark. It was creepy and it was
disturbing. It was um very adult, so
you know, [snorts] you are forewarned if
you are interested to read this, but I
really do love Sherlock Holmes and this
book did feel like fantasy Sherlock
Holmes and I have to admit the world
building was incredible. It was so
incredible. It is a world where there's
much higher humidity in the air and the
buildings and the way of life of the
people are intrinsically intertwined
with plants and plants can be just as
predatory as animals in this world. Two
books that I had to reread were Snow and
Rose, um a classic on this channel, and
Heartwood Hotel. Again, um two other
books that are really
close to my heart. It was time for a
reread of Howl's Moving Castle,
especially because I was motivated to
reread it due to this gorgeous gorgeous
cover and this limited edition version
of the book.
And I think it is such a special looking
book and
this book inspired me to rewatch some of
my favorite Studio Ghibli movies and I
actually watched My Neighbor Totoro for
the very first time. For one reason or
another, I just hadn't watched it until
now.
And I'm so happy I did. It was such a
special movie and of course I had to
rewatch Howl's Moving Castle as well.
This is not a book I've read yet, but my
number one book to finish reading before
the month is out is Mirrors in the Earth
amidst unprecedented ecological
devastation.
>> [clears throat]
>> It's easy to feel hopeless and
disconnected. It's easier still to
forget about our inherent goodness or to
discount the power of our inboard
empathy. For those of us who are highly
sensitive people, innately attuned to
the workings of the natural world, it
can be hard to embrace the belief that
we are enough as we are and that this
awareness can heal the Earth. It sounded
like an absolutely book. A viewer sent
it to me and I'm very grateful that they
did. I've mentioned this book already,
but it truly has become one of my
all-time favorite books. Circe by
Madeline Miller. I knew it was so
popular at the time that I first saw it
and so I didn't read it. I thought it
was maybe overhyped,
um but now that the interest in the book
has died down, I did want to take a look
and Madeline Miller is such an
incredible writer. The book has very
mature themes. There is definitely a lot
of disturbing things that happen in it,
especially traumatic events to the main
character. Books with those elements are
often difficult for me to read
and yet this book somehow just kept me
so engrossed page by page by page and
the ending just
was the [music] best ending to a book I
think I have ever ever read. What would
it be to be powerful and immortal? Why
we would never want to live that way and
why the life cycle and life and [music]
birth and death and pain and all these
things are so important and so intrinsic
to who we are and this book so
effectively told that story. I did
become part of a non-fiction book club
this year because I wanted to read more
non-fiction. I had recently read The
Heart of the Sea, which is one of my
favorite non-fiction books. It was so
good and so for this non-fiction book
club, we read In the Garden of the
Beasts, which was an incredible book,
one that I think everyone should read,
um as well as The Indifferent Stars
Above. And this book is just an amazing
amazing book. It is so educational. It
really submerged you in a whole
different era in American history and it
was so moving, so heartbreaking. It
showed the best and the worst of that
era and it also showed so many aspects
of that era that are still very relevant
today in terms of how we treat other
people and who we perceive as belonging
and not to our groups. It makes you just
amazed at the resilience of humanity and
it gives you hope, too. I really do feel
that you see what people have gone
through and that they've still gone
ahead and made the world a better place
and lived beautiful lives. It just
inspires you to keep going. I also
watched the movie Frankenstein by
Guillermo del Toro and I've been a fan
of his movies in the past, even though
they can be really hard to watch
sometimes, and so I really enjoyed it
and I did want to read the book
Frankenstein and even though I knew it
was quite different from the movie, I
did read it and it was very
thought-provoking and it was just kind
of amazing to read something that an
18-year-old wrote that was so original
and groundbreaking for a genre. And
yeah, it was a wild read. Um I don't
know if I'm going to read it again, but
I'm glad I did. I read El Mago de Oz in
Spanish or The Wizard of Oz because I've
been trying to listen to audiobooks with
my son who is learning both Spanish and
English and I thought it was actually
one of my favorite classic children's
books besides Anne of Green Gables. It
is so well written and so fun to read. I
am no doubt forgetting of so many books,
Watercolor in the Woods being one of
them that now just came through my mind.
I absolutely love that book. I've been
using it for so much inspiration for art
and it's one of the best watercolor
books I've found for a long time. I also
read The Highly Sensitive Parent, which
was an incredibly important book for me
to read. Book was so incredibly helpful
for helping me understand myself better
and learn how to manage these feelings
better in feeling very overstimulated
and how to respond to that and also
unlearning some things I had in my mind
with what I should be as a parent versus
what is the healthiest and more balanced
version of myself as a parent and I
think those are very important questions
for all parents to ask themselves, to
rewrite their internal narrative of what
they think is healthy, good, appropriate
parenthood to what actually helps for
the health and balance of both child and
the adult. So there you go. I wanted to
share with you at least some books that
I've been reading and enjoying. If I had
to pick my top ones for the year, it
would be these ones and I just wanted to
share with you. Next year, my goals are
once again to branch out into new genres
as well as to of course go back to my
tried and true favorites such as cozy
mysteries and cozy fantasy and
everything that feels wholesome and not
stressful whatsoever. I'm sending you
all so much love and thank you for
joining me here today for this very
bookish chat.